<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://airlegend.github.io/</id><title>Alvaro's blog</title><subtitle>Mostly at the intersection of computers, math and data.</subtitle> <updated>2023-11-30T22:39:52+01:00</updated> <author> <name>Alvaro</name> <uri>https://airlegend.github.io/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://airlegend.github.io/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://airlegend.github.io/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2023 Alvaro </rights> <icon>//assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>//assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Latent Consistency Models: How to speedup image generation</title><link href="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/lcm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Latent Consistency Models: How to speedup image generation" /><published>2023-11-28T04:33:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-11-30T22:39:51+01:00</updated> <id>https://airlegend.github.io/posts/lcm/</id> <content src="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/lcm/" /> <author> <name>Alvaro</name> </author> <category term="ML" /> <category term="Deep Learning" /> <summary> In a previous post I briefly covered Diffusion Models. And as I pointed out, they have an important drawback that makes them slow at creating new images. We often have to wait minutes for an image to be generated (even with beefy machines!). I’m talking about the “denoising” steps they have to run for generating an image. –Denoising steps of a Diffusion Model to produce an image– Reducing ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Some thoughts on the usage of AI for developing software: Is the end near?</title><link href="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/ai-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some thoughts on the usage of AI for developing software: Is the end near?" /><published>2023-11-27T08:33:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-11-30T17:08:25+01:00</updated> <id>https://airlegend.github.io/posts/ai-development/</id> <content src="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/ai-development/" /> <author> <name>Alvaro</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <category term="AI" /> <category term="Development" /> <summary> – Beware of the following to be quite philosophycal, if you're pragmatic, end the reading here! – In the last post I wrote about how I used AI as an assistant to build a guitar chord website. During that (short) venture I had the opportunity to reflect first hand on the future impact of AI on software development. So that’s what I’m sharing on this post. One of my first thoughts, and also... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>The AI Coder: Building a website using AI</title><link href="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/openchords/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The AI Coder: Building a website using AI" /><published>2023-11-25T03:33:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-11-30T22:39:51+01:00</updated> <id>https://airlegend.github.io/posts/openchords/</id> <content src="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/openchords/" /> <author> <name>Alvaro</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <category term="AI" /> <category term="Development" /> <summary> Last week I decided to tackle a quite silly side-project I left stopped about 2 years ago: building my own (guitar) chord / tab site so I can store all my music sheets. The main motivation for doing this is that I got tired of using UltimateGuitar, from which I’ve been being a user since around 2013. Back then it was vey handy to have a site where I could store all my guitar tabs, search for o... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How I generated professional headshots for my LinkedIn profile</title><link href="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/dreambooth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I generated professional headshots for my LinkedIn profile" /><published>2023-11-18T03:33:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-11-30T22:39:51+01:00</updated> <id>https://airlegend.github.io/posts/dreambooth/</id> <content src="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/dreambooth/" /> <author> <name>Alvaro</name> </author> <category term="ML" /> <category term="Deep Learning" /> <summary> The other day I was bored, wandering through LinkedIn and realized that I probably needed some new profile pics. You know, the ones very corporate-guys share on their posts. Something cool with a suit and some office-styled background. So I thought: What if I finetune an image generation model on myself and use it to generate them? How can I generate photos of myself? Just to begin, there are... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>LoRA: How can I tune my model without an expensive GPU?</title><link href="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/lora/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LoRA: How can I tune my model without an expensive GPU?" /><published>2023-10-30T04:33:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-10-30T04:33:00+01:00</updated> <id>https://airlegend.github.io/posts/lora/</id> <content src="https://airlegend.github.io/posts/lora/" /> <author> <name>Alvaro</name> </author> <category term="ML" /> <category term="Deep Learning" /> <summary> Training neural networks can be really tedious. Both in terms of methodological complexity – tuning hyperparameters, syncing training runs, scheduling learning rates, etc. – and also hardware requirements. That’s why historically large architectures (like ResNet) have been “pretrained”, or trained on broad tasks (image classification, segmentation, object detection, etc) by more-or-less powerf... </summary> </entry> </feed>
